Irene Andres

Cellphone: 469.767.4477

Dallas, TX – <u>irene.andres.sanchez@gmail.com</u> <u>https://es.linkedin.com/in/irene-andres/en</u>

OBJECTIVE: Dedicated and dynamic construction Project Manager with more than 3 years of experience combining project management and estimating of projects. Looking for a position as Project Engineer/Manager in a fast growth company. Willing to relocate.

EDUCATION:

B.S. Civil Engineering, Polytechnic University of Madrid. GPA: 3.3/4.0

09/2010-07/2014

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Altus Construction LLC, Houston, Dallas and Laredo, TX

09/2015 - Present

Project Manager and estimator in Heavy Highway Construction Company.

- Estimates projects for municipalities and TxDOT, being the lead estimator to three of the four last projects awarded in the 18 months.
- Creates project plans including the baseline schedule and budget, using Microsoft Project and Excel.
- Manages work on site through the superintendent.
- Proposes solutions to expedite the schedule.
- Designs possible solutions to discrepancies with the plans encountered at the field.
- Monitors progress ensuring that the project keeps on track, stays under budget and develops according to plan.
- Organizes and oversees sub-out work in different fields such as Electrical and Landscaping.
- Reports project results showing setbacks encountered.
- Succeeded in managing the following projects (including but not limited to):

Owner: Texas Department of Transportation

Project: Slope Failure Repairs Project on IH35E, Dallas

<u>Scope:</u> asphalt pavement, interlock concrete blocks for erosion control, retaining walls, earthworks and traffic control during night time.

Budget: \$6.1M (currently on planning phase, estimated start May 2018)

Owner: Harris County Flood Control District

Project: Countywide Channel Repairs Project

<u>Scope:</u> one-year maintenance project: drainage pipe installation, rip rap and granular fill installation, earthworks and concrete lining works.

Budget: \$4.7M (estimated deadline August 2018)

Owner: Texas Department of Transportation

Project: University Connection Hike and Bike Trail, Houston

Scope: three-span pedestrian bridge construction including illumination, retaining wall, concrete trail,

landscaping.

Budget: \$2.5M (estimated deadline March 2018)

Owner: City of Laredo

Project: Zacate Creek Channel Improvements, Laredo

Scope: Earthworks (embankment and excavation), fabric form concrete installation, dewatering.

Budget: \$1.4M (completed on April 2017 one month ahead of schedule and under budget)

Owner: North Texas Tollway Authority

Project: Slope rehabilitation President George Bush Turnpike, Carrolton

Scope: Earthwork (excavation, fine grading)

Budget: \$210K (completed on July 2016 two months ahead of schedule and \$45K under budget).

General Contractor: Pogue Construction

Project: Emma Ousley Middle School competition football field, Arlington

Scope: Earthwork, conc. pave. demolition and replacement and storm drain line installation.

Budget: \$360K (completed on July 2016 on time and \$30K under budget).

Todeca Topoperforaciones LLC, Salamanca, Spain

09/2014-06/2015

Civil Engineer in Company specialized in Horizontal Directional Drillings.

- Optimized and improved work through upgrading company standards and processes.
- Supported tender bids.
- Created detailed excavation and drilling drawings with AutoCAD.
- Supervised several horizontal directional drilling projects by carryout periodical site visits.
- Encouraged continuous improvement through cost control.

SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE:

- ✓ Microsoft Project ✓ CypeCAD
- ✓ MS Office + Microsoft Outlook ✓ Civil 3D AutoCAD and 2D AutoCAD

LANGUAGES:

- ✓ English: full professional proficiency.
- ✓ Spanish: native language.